Guide to the Records of Gallatin Award Dinners 1957-1985 RG 37.18
New York University Archives
Records of Gallatin Award Dinners
1957-1985
RG 37.18
New York University Archives
5.5 linear feet 5.5 linear feet (11 boxes)
The Albert Gallatin Associates, established in 1956 by New York University alumni, constitute a community of concerned individuals who demonstrate by their continuing support their confidence in the University's educational leadership. Donors are honored at annual awards dinners. This collection contains printed records and photograhs of Gallatin Awards Dinners from the years 1957 to 1985.
Gallatin Associates.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject/author heading then chronologically within each subject/author heading.
The files are grouped into one series.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains records of Gallatin Award Dinners from 1957-1985. Documentation includes printed material from the dinners, programs, copies of the Gallatin Bulletin, information on Gallatin Medalists, invitation lists, seating charts, dinner budgets and photographs.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Albert Gallatin Associates, established by alumni in 1956, include individuals, foundations and corporations who demonstrate their confidence in the University's educational leadership in the urban community. In the tradition of Albert Gallatin, statesman, scholar, and financier, cofounder and first president of New York University's first governing council, the Associates provide support for faculty, fellowships, scholarships, educational and research programs, and new facilities.
Gallatin Associates recognize the vital significance of unrestricted gifts to the University or to a particular school, college, or division. Yearly unrestricted support provides New York University with the flexibility to respond to the intellectual, cultural, and scientific needs of the community it serves. The Associates also meet with the president, deans and faculty to discuss University affairs and offer the benefit of their experience and judgment. As the University's special representatives to the nonacademic community, the Gallatins share their enthusiasm and pride of affiliation to enlist the participation of their friends and colleagues.
All members receive regular communications informing them of current University activities. In addition, Gallatins are invited to University-sponsored events, including previews of exhibitions at the Grey Art Gallery, special lecture series, seminars, concerts, and other cultural events. Gallatins have honored guest status at the University's commencement exercises. They also may avail themselves of reading privileges at the Elmer Holmes Bobst Library and Study Center.
Sources:
Identification of item, date (if known); Records of the Gallatin Award Dinners; collection number; box number; folder number; New York University Archives, New York University Libraries.
Access Restrictions
Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection.
Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted.
This collection is in
off-site storage
.
Provenance
This collection was transferred to the University Archives from the Development Office in 1987.
Gallatin, Albert, 1761-1849; New York University.; Annual giving.; Award dinners; awards.; Financial records.; Invitations.; Memorabilia.; New York (State) |z New York.; Pamphlets.; Photographs.
- Series I
  - Gallatin Dinners, 1957-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Bar code: 3 1142 04225698 5
  - Gallatin Dinners, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Gallatin Dinner, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Gallatin Dinner, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Gallatin Dinner, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Gallatin Dinner, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Gallatin Dinner, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Gallatin Dinner, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Gallatin Dinner, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Bar code: 3 1142 04225699 3
  - Fellow Dinners, Nov 16, 1970-Oct 6, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Gallatin Fellows Dinner, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Gallatin Dinner, Dec 1, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Annual Dinners, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - New Gallatins, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Gallatin Dinner, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Gallatin Dinner Expenditures, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner Printed Material, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Bar code: 3 1142 04225700 9
  - Gallatin Associates Seventeenth Annual Reception Dinner and Dance, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner Expenditures, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner General Correspondence, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner Printed Material, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner Expenditures, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner General Correspondence, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner Printed Material, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Gallatin Medalist, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Gallatin Bulletin, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner Expenditures, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Bar code: 3 1142 04225701 7
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner Printed Material, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Gallatin Medalist, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Phelps Lectures Dinners, Oct 28, 1976-Nov 18, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Gallatin Bulletin, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Annual Reports, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Gallatin Dinner, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Gallatin Dinner Expenditures, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Gallatin Dinner Printed Material for Invitations, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Gallatin Medalist, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Gallatin Associates General, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Gallatin Fellows Dinner, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Gallatin Fellows Awards, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Real Estate Institute Dinner, Mar 24, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Fellows Dinner I, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Bar code: 3 1142 04225702 5
  - Gallatin Fellows Dinner, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Gallatin Fellows Dinner Photos, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Gallatin Dinner Regrets-Mag Card List, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Gallatin Dinner Accepts-Mag Card List, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Gallatin Dinner Printed Material, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Gallatin Dinner Miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Gallatin Dinner, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Bar code: 3 1142 04225703 3
  - Gallatin Bulletin, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Fellows Dinners: Remarks and Tributes, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Gallatin Fellows Dinner, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Gallatin Fellows Dinner cont., 1979 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Gallatin Nominations, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Bar code: 3 1142 04225704 1
  - Gallatin Bulletin, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Gallatin Fellows Dinner, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Gallatin Medalist, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Program, Oct 2, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Waldorf Astoria, Oct 2, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Albert Gallatin Medalist Jerome Coles, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Gallatin Fellows Dinner, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Bar code: 3 1142 04225705 8
  - Gallatin Fellows Dinner cont., 1981 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Gallatin Dinner, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Gallatin Dinner Program, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Gallatin Dinner Award/Citation, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Gallatin Dinner Seating, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Gallatin Dinner Budget, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Waldorf Astoria, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Bar code: 3 1142 04225706 6
  - Gallatin Dinner Remarks, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Gallatin Dinner Invitations, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Gallatin Dinner Printed Program, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner Entertainment, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner Photographs, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner Invitations, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner Medalist/Family Invitations, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner Attendance, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner Seating Requests, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner Program, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner Citation/Medal/Portfolio, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Bar code: 3 1142 04225707 4
  - Gallatin Cumulative Donations for period, Sep 1, 1984-Apr 30, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Mailing Gallatin Committee Invite, Apr 1985 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Master Schedule, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Master Schedule 2, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Invitations, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Invitations Lists and Acceptances, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Medal Citation Order, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Budget, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - $1,000 Donors for the month, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Printed Program, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Bar code: 3 1142 04225708 2
  - Gallatin Associates Fellows, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Gallatin Associates Executive Leadership, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Gallatin Associates Lists Maintenance, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Gallatin Associates Winter Gala, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Gallatin Fellows, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Membership Carbons, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - NYU Club, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - John Schiff, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Gallatin Board - List and Silverman Letters, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)